<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eyoel Meles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eyoel Meles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:39:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Better</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/get_better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:39:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/get_better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-better&#34;&gt;Get Better&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lack of skill, a lot of times show a lack of confidence in diving into the unknown, unwilling to be uncomfortable for a long period of time, unable to feel dumb for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a lot of people have been too comfortable in their life for a very long time.&#xA;we have been aforded a lot of convincies through out the years, as humanity gets to evolve and we have got really lazy, &lt;strong&gt;Specially Mentally&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RISC V</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/risc-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:05:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/risc-v/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dumping-random-scattered-knowledge-on-risc-v&#34;&gt;Dumping Random Scattered Knowledge on RISC-V&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The RISC architecture emerged from the need to simplify instruction sets, improve speed, and exploit advancements in Very Large Scale Integration (VLSI) and compiler technology. The core idea behind RISC is to streamline instructions to make execution faster and more efficient, often completing each instruction in one clock cycle.&#xA;can you explain the previous note, what does VLSI and Compiler technology mean, and what does it mean to streamline instruction so it complete each instruction ini one clock cycle mean?&#xA;LLM served by Perplexity Labs&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to break down the note and explain the key terms.&#xA;RISC Architecture&#xA;RISC stands for Reduced Instruction Set Computing. It&amp;rsquo;s a type of computer architecture that aims to simplify the instruction set of a computer processor. The goal is to make the processor faster and more efficient by reducing the number of instructions it needs to execute.&#xA;VLSI (Very Large Scale Integration)&#xA;VLSI refers to the process of integrating a large number of transistors onto a single silicon chip. In the 1970s and 1980s, advancements in VLSI technology allowed for the creation of more complex and powerful microprocessors. This led to the development of RISC architectures, which took advantage of the increased transistor density to implement more efficient instruction sets.&#xA;Compiler Technology&#xA;A compiler is a software program that translates high-level programming languages (like C or Java) into machine code that a computer processor can execute. Advances in compiler technology allowed for better optimization of code, which meant that compilers could generate more efficient machine code that took advantage of the simplified instruction sets of RISC architectures.&#xA;Streamlining Instructions&#xA;In traditional computer architectures, instructions were often complex and took multiple clock cycles to execute. A clock cycle is the time it takes for a processor to execute a single instruction. Streamlining instructions means breaking down complex instructions into simpler ones that can be executed more quickly.&#xA;In RISC architectures, instructions are designed to be simple and execute in a single clock cycle. This is achieved by:&#xA;Reducing the number of instructions: By eliminating complex instructions, RISC architectures reduce the number of instructions that need to be executed.&#xA;Simplifying instruction formats: RISC instructions have a simpler format, making it easier for the processor to decode and execute them.&#xA;Using pipelining: Pipelining is a technique where the processor breaks down the execution of an instruction into a series of stages, each of which can be executed in a single clock cycle.&#xA;Completing each instruction in one clock cycle&#xA;In RISC architectures, the goal is to complete each instruction in a single clock cycle. This means that the processor can execute an instruction in the time it takes for a single clock pulse to occur. This is achieved by:&#xA;Using simple instructions that don&amp;rsquo;t require multiple clock cycles to execute.&#xA;Implementing pipelining, which allows the processor to execute multiple stages of an instruction in a single clock cycle.&#xA;Using a large number of registers, which allows the processor to access data quickly and execute instructions more efficiently.&#xA;By completing each instruction in a single clock cycle, RISC architectures can achieve higher instruction-level parallelism (ILP), which means that the processor can execute more instructions per clock cycle, leading to improved performance and efficiency.&#xA;what does a cycle count mean?&#xA;LLM served by Perplexity Labs&#xA;In computer architecture, a cycle count refers to the number of clock cycles required to execute a particular instruction or a sequence of instructions. A clock cycle is the time it takes for a processor to execute a single instruction or a part of an instruction.&#xA;Think of a clock cycle like a heartbeat of the processor. Each clock cycle is a discrete unit of time, and the processor executes a specific task or instruction during each cycle.&#xA;The cycle count is a measure of how many clock cycles are needed to complete a specific task or instruction. For example:&#xA;A simple instruction like &amp;ldquo;ADD A, B&amp;rdquo; might have a cycle count of 1, meaning it takes only 1 clock cycle to execute.&#xA;A more complex instruction like &amp;ldquo;LOAD A, [MEMORY ADDRESS]&amp;rdquo; might have a cycle count of 3, meaning it takes 3 clock cycles to execute.&#xA;A sequence of instructions like &amp;ldquo;LOOP 10 TIMES&amp;rdquo; might have a cycle count of 10, meaning it takes 10 clock cycles to execute the entire loop.&#xA;The cycle count is important because it affects the performance of the processor. A lower cycle count generally means that the processor can execute instructions faster and more efficiently.&#xA;Here are some common cycle counts:&#xA;1 cycle: Simple instructions like arithmetic operations (e.g., ADD, SUB) or register transfers (e.g., MOV).&#xA;2-3 cycles: Instructions that access memory, like LOAD or STORE.&#xA;4-5 cycles: Instructions that perform complex arithmetic operations, like DIV or MUL.&#xA;10-20 cycles: Instructions that perform complex tasks, like branching or looping.&#xA;Keep in mind that cycle counts can vary depending on the specific processor architecture, instruction set, and implementation.&#xA;In the context of RISC architectures, the goal is to minimize the cycle count for each instruction, ideally executing each instruction in a single clock cycle. This allows for faster execution and improved performance.&#xA;one feature of RISC is Large Register sets, can you explain it in detail, and in a more technical way&#xA;LLM served by Perplexity Labs&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details of large register sets in RISC architectures.&#xA;What are registers?&#xA;In computer architecture, a register is a small amount of on-chip memory that stores data temporarily while it&amp;rsquo;s being processed by the CPU. Registers are the fastest type of memory, and they&amp;rsquo;re used to hold data that&amp;rsquo;s being actively used by the CPU.&#xA;Why are large register sets important in RISC?&#xA;In RISC architectures, large register sets are a key feature that enables efficient execution of instructions. Here are some reasons why:&#xA;Reduced memory access: By having a large number of registers, the CPU can store more data locally, reducing the need to access slower main memory. This reduces the number of memory accesses, which can be a significant bottleneck in CPU performance.&#xA;Improved instruction-level parallelism: With more registers available, the CPU can execute more instructions in parallel, improving instruction-level parallelism (ILP). This is because the CPU can use multiple registers to store operands for different instructions, allowing them to be executed simultaneously.&#xA;Simplified instruction encoding: Large register sets enable simpler instruction encoding, as the CPU can use a smaller number of bits to specify the register operands. This reduces the instruction size, making it easier to decode and execute instructions.&#xA;Characteristics of large register sets in RISC&#xA;Here are some key characteristics of large register sets in RISC architectures:&#xA;Number of registers: RISC architectures typically have 32 or more registers, although some designs may have as many as 128 or more.&#xA;Register width: Registers in RISC architectures are typically 32 bits or 64 bits wide, although some designs may use wider registers (e.g., 128 bits).&#xA;Register organization: Registers are often organized into a flat register file, where each register has a unique identifier (e.g., R0, R1, &amp;hellip;, R31).&#xA;Register allocation: Registers are allocated dynamically by the compiler or runtime environment, using techniques like register allocation algorithms or register renaming.&#xA;Technical benefits of large register sets&#xA;Here are some technical benefits of large register sets in RISC architectures:&#xA;Reduced register spilling: With more registers available, the CPU is less likely to spill registers to memory, reducing the number of memory accesses and improving performance.&#xA;Improved register allocation: Large register sets enable more efficient register allocation, reducing the number of register conflicts and improving instruction-level parallelism.&#xA;Simplified instruction scheduling: With more registers available, instruction scheduling becomes simpler, as the CPU can use multiple registers to store operands for different instructions.&#xA;Better support for out-of-order execution: Large register sets enable better support for out-of-order execution, as the CPU can use multiple registers to store operands for different instructions, improving instruction-level parallelism.&#xA;Examples of RISC architectures with large register sets&#xA;Here are some examples of RISC architectures with large register sets:&#xA;MIPS: The MIPS RISC architecture has 32 registers, each 32 bits wide.&#xA;SPARC: The SPARC RISC architecture has 32 registers, each 32 bits wide, although some variants may have more registers.&#xA;ARM: The ARM RISC architecture has 16 registers, each 32 bits wide, although some variants may have more registers.&#xA;PowerPC: The PowerPC RISC architecture has 32 registers, each 64 bits wide.&#xA;In summary, large register sets are a key feature of RISC architectures, enabling efficient execution of instructions, improved instruction-level parallelism, and simplified instruction encoding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Paper with AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:25:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;writing-academic-papers-with-ai&#34;&gt;Writing academic papers with AI&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;[TL;DR]&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key takeways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Do&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI or AI tools mainly should be used for better writing, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not let the AI do the Thinking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; this kills the authenticity and credibility of the author. the AI should not claim an idea, it should come from the authors understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let AI or AI tools alther the figures, this could basically be considered as faking the results&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
